A Guide to the Virginia Geological Survey, Records, 1834-1903
Library of Virginia
- Series I: Correspondence of William B. Rogers, 1836-1903
  - Correspondence to William B. Rogers, 1844-1903 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - J[ames] Brown, Jr., Richmond, to William B. Rogers, University of Virginia, February 17, 1849, J[ames] Brown, Jr., Richmond, to William B. Rogers, University of Virginia, inquiring after his health; informing him that some members of the legislature might attempt to provide for the publication of his geological report and that he doubted there would be concerted opposition, especially if Rogers would come to Richmond and speak to the members, as there were only a few of them who even recalled that there had been a geological survey made; asking him that if he could not come himself, to send Brown such published reports as he could spare and a brief sketch of his plans for a final report so that Brown might argue in his favor. 2 pp. with address leaf.
    - [William B. Rogers], University of Virginia, to James Brown, Jr., [Richmond], February 25, 1849, [William B. Rogers], University of Virginia, to James Brown, Jr., [Richmond], mentioning a separate bundle of reports sent to Brown; enclosing a copy of his geological map which had excited much favorable comment when it was shown at the British Association, the Royal Geological Society, and the French Academy by Henry D. Rogers; stating that a "nervous debility" prevented him from speaking to the General Assembly, but that he would speak to a few members if Brown thought it needful; and presenting an elaborate outline of the proposed report, consisting of a map, section drawings, and illustrations to exhibit the "geological anatomy" of the state, and a text describing the various regions in detail, with chemical analyses of the ores, minerals, and waters. 6 pp., incomplete draft.
    - [William B. Rogers], Boston, Massachusetts, to [Josiah Parsons Cooke, Harvard University], December 26, 1853, [William B. Rogers], Boston, Massachusetts, to [Josiah Parsons Cooke, Harvard University], declaring his intention of returning briefly to Virginia to reorganize the geological survey and provide for the publication of the final report in response to a query from Cooke about organizing and supervising a geological survey of Massachusetts; cautioning supporters of the survey from exaggerating the immediate economic benefits of such a survey; stressing the importance of looking to the long, rather than short, term value of the survey; and outlining in seven points the long term benefits which would result from the survey to the advantage of the entire state and her citizens. 5 pp., incomplete draft. Josiah Parsons Cooke (October 12, 1827-September 3, 1894), founder of the department of chemistry at Harvard in 1850 at the age of 23 and later president of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.
    - [William B. Rogers], Boston, Massachusetts, to Frank G. Ruffin, n.p., December 27, 1853, [William B. Rogers], Boston, Massachusetts, to Frank G. Ruffin, n.p., acknowledging receipt of his letter of December 6; expressing his gratitude for the interest displayed by Ruffin and the Agricultural Society in Rogers's geological map and planned report; informing Ruffin of his intention to ask the General Assembly for funds to revise the map and publish his report and of his plans to visit Richmond during the session; declaring that while he appreciates the interest and ehop of anone so inclined, he prefers that his work stand on its own merits and on his reputation, rather than depending upon the testimony of some foreign expert for it s success or failure in the legislature; and discussing the pros and cons of proposed county geological maps and of a scientific department Ruffin was interested in organizing. 7 pp., typescript. Frank Gildart Ruffin (December 1, 1816-June 4, 1892), was at this time editor of the Southern Planter magazine and served as Second Auditor of Virginia from January 1, 1884, until his death.
    - W. B. Rogers, Boston, Massachusetts, to F[rank] G. Ruffin, n.p., December 29, 1853, W. B. Rogers, Boston, Massachusetts, to F[rank] G. Ruffin, n.p., acknowledging receipt of his letter of December 25; mentioning Rogers's lengthy reply on December 27; saying that one reason he left his teaching post at the University of Virginia was so he might concentrate on having his report published; advising Ruffin's society not to attempt too much; and agreeing in principle to Ruffin's request that he give some lectures when in Virginia. 2 pp., typescript.
    - D. T. Bisbie, Mecklenburg County, to W. B. Rogers, University of Virginia, June 15, 1854, D. T. Bisbie, Mecklenburg County, to W. B. Rogers, University of Virginia, describing a copper mine "in an adjoining County" which he and some other men own; giving an unsubstantiated report of an analysis of the ore; and asking for an opinion, based on his description, as to whether the geological indications point to yellow pyrites or sulphuret. 3 pp. with address leaf, torn.
    - Emma Rogers (Mrs. W. B. Rogers), Boston, Massachusetts, to W[illiam] W. Scott, Librarian of State Library, Richmond, May 10, 1903, Emma Rogers (Mrs. W. B. Rogers), Boston, Massachusetts, to W[illiam] W. Scott, enclosing letters relating to the geological survey of Virginia, to be placed with similar material sent by her to the library two or more years earlier. 2 pp. William Wallace Scott (1845-1929) was acting state librarian in 1903. He resigned to become state law librarian in that year.
- Series II: Reports, sections, lists and field notes, 1834-1884
  The reports, sections, lists and field notes are from the geologists including William B. Rogers. Many are undated. Bound volumes are included.
  Arranged by geologist.
  - William E. A. Aikin, 1837 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - William E. A. Aikin, [1837], Report on the geology of Lee, Russell, Scott, and Washington Counties. 90 pp., incomplete.
    - William E. A. Aikin, [1837], Geological sections of Lee, Russell, Scott, and Washington counties, to accompany the report above. 19 parts, of which numbers 10 and 13 are missing.
  - William E. A. Aikin, 1838 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - William E. A. Aikin, [1838], Report on the geology of Lee, Russell, Scott, and Washington Counties, intended in part as a revision of the report of 1837. 32 pp.
    - William E. A. Aikin, 1838, Geological sections of Lee, Russell, Scott, and Washington counties, to accompany the report above. 13 parts.
  - George W. Boyd, 1839-1840 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - George W. Boyd, 1839, Field notes. Southern Primary Region. Volume I. 1 vol., 116 pp.
    - George W. Boyd, 1839, Field notes. Southern Primary Region. Volume II. 1 vol., 42 pp.
    - George W. Boyd, 1840, Field notes. Rough notes on geology of northern Virginia, April 28-September 19, 1840. 60 pp.
    - George W. Boyd, 1840, Field notes. Northern Primary District. Finished transcription of rough notes above, covering same dates. Entries from September 11 through September 19 in the handwriting of James B. Rogers, June 24- August 14, 1841. 1 vol., 132 pp.
    - George W. Boyd, n.d., List. Fossils of Virginia. Arranged by strata, in the handwriting of George W. Boyd. 1 vol., 23 pp.
  - Caleb Briggs, Jr., 1840 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., 1840, List. Boxes [of specimens] collected by C. Briggs. Also contains notes by Charles B. Hayden on the geology of Hampshire County, n.d. 1 vol., 42 pp.
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d., List. Catalogue of Rocks. 1 vol., 125 pp.
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d., List. Catalogue of Rocks. Vol. IV. 1 vol., 163 pp.
  - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d., Report. Valley River and Buffalo Creek Section. Includes sketch map of the area. 47 pp.
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d., Report. White Day Creek Section and Prickets Creek. Includes sketch map of the area. 28 pp.
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d., Report. Geological Examinations on the Monongalia and its Tributaries, Deckers Creek and Scots Run. Includes sketch map of the area. 58 pp.
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d., Report. Appendix to Notes. In vicinity of Cheat River. 3 pp.
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d., Report. Of the Big Sandy Section. 20 pp.
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d., Report. Clarksburg to Parkersburg. 46 pp.
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d., Report. North Western Turnpike. Cheat River to Clarksburg and the Head of Limestone Creek. 20 pp.
  - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d., Report. Section from Beverly by Weston to Parkersburg. 33 pp.
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d., Report. Section from the Rich Mountain by Bullstown to the Ohio at Parkersburg. 35 pp.
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d., Report. Section from the North Fork of the South Branch of the Potomac by the way of Clarksburg to the Ohio River at the mouth of Fishing Creek. 41 pp.
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d., Report. [Geology of the Proctors Run-Fishing Creek area near the Ohio River]. 30 pp.
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d., Report. Main Coal Seam, Upper Coal Series [near the Ohio River]. 30 pp.
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d., Report. Valley of the Ohio. 44 pp.
    - Caleb Briggs, Jr., n.d., Report. Formation XII. Conglomerate on the Eastern Margin of the Ohio Basin. 25 pp.
  - Charles B. Hayden, 1836-1837 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Charles B. Hayden, 1836, Field notes. No. 2. Gold Region [of Louisa and Buckingham Counties]. August 8-20. Some entries in the handwriting of William B. Rogers and A. Maxwell Walker. 1 vol., 68 pp.
    - Charles B. Hayden, 1836, Field notes. Rappahannock. [Hanover County to Gloucester County.] September 12-October 29. Inverted and at back of volume: field notes of William B. Rogers, July-August 1838, on the geology observed in the vicinity of Lynchburg, Botetourt County, and Lexington. 1 vol., 136 pp.
    - Charles B. Hayden, 1836, Field notes. Geology of the Shenandoah Valley region from Rockingham County to Harpers Ferry. September 15-October 3. 1 vol., 35 pp.
    - Charles B. Hayden, 1836?, Field notes. Rough notes, undated, covering much the same territory as the volume immediately above. 1 vol., 46 pp.
    - Charles B. Hayden, 1837, Field notes. Tertiary Region [of Tidewater Virginia near James River]. March-May. 1 vol., 132 pp.
  - Charles B. Hayden, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Charles B. Hayden, 1837, Field notes. Continuation of volume immediately above. 1 vol., 28 pp.
    - Charles B. Hayden, 1837, Field notes. Tertiary Region. Continuation of volume immediately above. 1 vol., 43 pp.
    - Charles B. Hayden, 1837, Field notes. Geology of the Shenandoah Valley region from Augusta County to Jefferson County, and westward to Hampshire County. July. 1 vol., 84 pp.
    - Charles B. Hayden, 1837, Field notes. Continuation of volume immediately above. 1 vol., 21 pp.
    - Charles B. Hayden, 1837, Field notes. Springs. Charts showing date, time, and temperature for various hot springs in western Virginia. November. 1 vol., 21 pp.
  - Charles B. Hayden, 1838-1839 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Charles B. Hayden, 1838, Report on the Northern District and the James River Tertiary. January. In two parts: Northern Appalachian Region, 54 pp., with 15 pp. of sections; on the country bordering on James River and its tributaries, 23 pp.
    - Charles B. Hayden, 1838, Field notes. Appalachian Region [largely Hampshire and Frederick counties]. July-September. 1 vol., 112 pp.
    - Charles B. Hayden, 1838, Field notes. Continuation of volume immediately above. Also contains April 1851, in handwriting of William B. Rogers, Trip to Rivanna Mills. 1 vol., 29 pp.
    - Charles B. Hayden, 1839, Report. Pendleton and Bath counties. 22 pp.
    - Charles B. Hayden, 1839, Report. Miocene Tertiary of the counties south of James River. 48 pp.
  - Samuel Lewis, 1840 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Samuel Lewis, 1840, Field notes. Notes of Geological examinations in Virginia Commenced June 24, 1840, Chesterfield coal field. June 24-November 4. 2 vols., 179 and 47 pp.
  - Samuel Lewis, 1840 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Samuel Lewis, 1840, Report. Report of Samuel Lewis, one of the assistant geologists of the State of Virginia for the year 1840, containing a brief account of his operations during the summer and fall seasons. November 9. 7 pp.
  - A. McCall, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - A. McCall, n.d., Report. Description of salt production, especially of William King's salt well, Washington County. See also letters of July 25, 1840, and May 16, 1841, for mention of other salt wells. 2 pp.
  - Thomas S. Ridgeway, Jr., 1839-1840 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Thomas S. Ridgeway, Jr., 1839, Field notes. Geology of Bath and Highland counties. Also contains: notes on the rocks of the Potomac Coal Basin, in the handwriting of William B. Rogers, n.d.; notes on the geology of northwestern Virginia, primarily Hampshire and Preston counties, in the handwriting of Thomas S. Ridgeway, Jr., n.d.; Measurements of Rocks, in the hnadwriting of William B. Rogers, n.d.; Maatinal Series, in the handwriting of William B. Rogers, n.d,; and geological sections to accompany the notes on Bath and Highland counties first mentioned above, in the handwriting of Thomas S. Ridgeway, n.d. 1 vol., 239 pp.
    - Thomas S. Ridgeway, Jr., 1840, Field notes. Coal Sections on Big Kanawha River. April 23-. 1 vol., 55 pp.
  - Thomas S. Ridgeway, Jr., 1840-1841 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Thomas S. Ridgeway, Jr., 1840, Report. Description of a part of the section from Abbs Valley by Logan Court House to Guayandotte on the Ohio River. 3 pp.
    - Thomas S. Ridgeway, Jr., 1840, Sections. (Nos. 1-5 filed oversize). 1. Section at the Burning Spring on the Kanawha River. 1 p.; 2. Section at Mr. Joel Shrewsbury's Salt Works on the Kanawha River. 1 p.; 3. Section at Keller's Creek on the Kanawha river, 1 p.; 4. Section of Vineyard Hill. 1 p.; 5. Profile Section from Parkersburg along the Little Kanawha to Bulltown. 1 p.; 6. Profile Section from Round Bottom on Big Sandy along Tug Fork to Pigeon Creek. 1 p.
    - Thomas S. Ridgeway, Jr., 1841, Field notes. Notes of the Geological Survey conducted in the North Western District of Virginia. 1 vol., 48 pp.
  - Henry D. Rogers, 1834-1836 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Henry D. Rogers, 1834, Field notes. Journey to the coal region [of Pennsylvania, from Philadelphia]. April 5-6. Also contains: Geological Rambles in New Jersey, May 3-28; Journey from Richmond to Fredericksburg, etc., to Philadelphia, n.d.; From New York to Albany, n.d.; notes of electrical experiments made in October 1833 with William B. Rogers, and in his handwriting; and notes on the geology of Pennsylvania in the vicinity of Harrisburg. 1 vol., 138 pp.
    - Henry D. Rogers, 1836?, Field notes. Geology of the State of New Jersey, 1 vol., 150 pp.
  - James B. Rogers, 1837-1838 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - James B. Rogers, 1837, Field notes. Rough notes in handwriting of Charles B. Hayden on Tertiary Region of Tidewater Virginia near James River, May 26-27, 7 pp. Notes in handwriting of James B. Rogers on geology of Monroe and Giles counties, June 19-, 80 pp. Inverted at back of volume: geological sections and notes on vicinity of Bath County in handwriting of William B. Rogers, n.d., 38 pp. 1 vol.
    - James B. Rogers, 1837, Field notes. Geology of Augusta, Bath, and Highland counties. July. 1 vol., 84 pp.
    - James B. Rogers, 1837, Fragment of "A Map of the State of Virginia" by Herman Boye, 1827, showing part of southside Virginia, from Cumberland County south to Mecklenburg County, Mounted on linen and marked "JBR 1837."
    - James B. Rogers, 1838, Report. On the Middle District. Part 1st. January. Geology of Augusta, Bath, and Highland, Pendleton, and Pocahontas counties. 35 pp.
  - James B. Rogers, 1838-1841 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - James B. Rogers, 1838, Field notes. Geology of the Warm Springs region, including Bath, Botetourt, Giles, and Monroe counties. April. 1 vol., 28 pp.
    - James B. Rogers, 1838, Field notes. Geology of Alleghany, Bath, Craig, and Rockbridge counties, with particular attention to iron works. July-August. 1 vol., 63 pp.
    - James B. Rogers, 1838, Field notes. Middle district. Geology of Alleghany, Augusta, Bath, Botetourt, and Rockbridge counties. August-September. 1 vol., 68 pp.
    - James B. Rogers, 1839, Field notes. Geology of the region along the Jackson's, New, Gauley, Kanawha, and Elk rivers, with particular attention to coal seams. Includes instructions for the season in the handwriting of William B. Rogers. May. 1 vol., 130 pp.
    - James B. Rogers, 1839, Geological sections of Greenbrier and Fayette counties. 10 parts.
    - James B. Rogers, 1841, Field notes. Potomac Furnace to Leesburg, and then to Dranesville. August 4-7. 4 pp.
    - James B. Rogers, n.d., Field notes. Geology of northern Virginia and Maryland between Frederick and Boonesboro. 1 vol., 31 pp.
  - Robert E. Rogers, 1836 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Robert E. Rogers, 1836, Field notes. Northern Neck. April-June. Second volume also contains field notes in handwriting of William B. Rogers on geology from Charlottesville to Alleghany County, September 8-27. 2 vols., 232 pp.
    - Robert E. Rogers, 1836, Field notes. Geology of Fairfax County and vicinity. August. Also contains "Journey from Luray across the Massanutten Mn." in the handwriting of James B. Rogers, n.d., and "Memoranda, January 1837" in the handwriting of William B. Rogers on a coal seam discovered near Leakesville, North Carolina. 1 vol., 38 pp.
    - Robert E. Rogers, 1836, Field notes. Geology of northern Virginia, including Berkeley, Jefferson, Loudoun, and Morgan counties. September. 1 vol., 62 pp.
    - Robert E. Rogers, 1836, Field notes. "Summary of Swift Run Gap." Also contains instructions for the season in the handwriting of William B. Rogers. 1 vol., 30 pp.
  - William B. Rogers, 1835-1836 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - William B. Rogers, 1835, Field notes. Geology of region along the Pamunkey River, including King William and Hanover counties. July. Also contains a list of "Rocks of the Blue Ridge," n.d., and "Minutes of Analysis of soils," November. 1 vol., 39 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, 1835, Analyses of Marl, Sand, and Soils. 1 vol., 43 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, 1836, Field notes. Geology of part of North Carolina, Carroll County, the lead mines in Wythe County, the coal seams of southwestern and northwestern Virginia, and coal mines of northwestern Virginia and Maryland in the vicinity of Westernport. 1 vol., 202 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, 1836, Notes respecting the geology, etc., of the Miocene Marl region of Virginia [Tidewater]. 1 vol., 13 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, 1836, Report. Lower Tertiary or eocene of the Pamunkey. 16 pp. See Report of the Geological Reconnoissance of the State of Virginia, 1836, pp. 38-43.
    - William B. Rogers, 1836, Report. Materials collected for a detailed Report of the Survey in 1836: 1) Northern Neck and counties on south side of Rappahannock; 2) Coals of Chesterfield, etc., Analysis. 138 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, 1836, List. Eocene and Miocene Marls [Tidewater Virginia, 1836-1837]. 1 vol., 218 pp.
  - William B. Rogers, 1837 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - William B. Rogers, 1837, Field notes. Geology of Mercer and Monroe counties in the southwest, and Shenandoah and Hampshire counties in the north. August. 1 vol., 78 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, 1837, Field notes. Geology of Augusta, Bath, Hardy, Highland, and Pendleton counties. August. 1 vol., 100 pp.
  - William B. Rogers, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - William B. Rogers, 1839, Report. Drafts of Reports of the Progress of the Geological Survey of the State of Virginia for the year 1839, in the handwriting of William B. Rogers and Thomas S. Ridgeway, Jr. 78 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, 1839, Field notes. Miscellaneous notes on rocks, slates, and coke. 4 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, 1839?, Geological sections along Brandywine and Wissahickon creeks, Chester County, Pennsylvania. William B. Rogers visited this area in 1839. 7 parts.
    - William B. Rogers, 1839?, Geological sections in Pennsylvania from Pottstown west in the general direction of Reading, in handwriting of Willliam B. Rogers, who visited this area in 1839. 1 part, incomplete.
  - William B. Rogers, 1841-1844 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - William B. Rogers, 1841, Field notes. Geology of New York and eastern Canada, by William B. Rogers and Henry D. Rogers, August. Also contains notes on the Tertiary near Richmond, July, and notes made on a "Journey from Baltimore to Harper's Ferry," n.d. First page contains a list of "Boxes of Minerals, 1840." 1 vol., 123 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, 1841?, Field notes. Geology of western Virginia along the North Western Turnpike. 1 vol., 21 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, 1843, Field notes. Geology of northwestern Virginia. June-August. 1 vol., 225 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, 1844, Field notes. Geological Memoranda. Summer of 1843[4]. July-September. Concerns primarily the travels of William B. Rogers with the Pennsylvania artist Russell Smith, from Albemarle County to Alleghany County, then to Kanawha County, and returning by way of Highland County. Also contains expense accounts of Russell Smith, and lists of sketches made by him (see Oversize, Box 6).
  - William B. Rogers, 1853-1877 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - William B. Rogers, 1853, Field notes. Geology of route between Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, and Baltimore, Maryland; the vicinity of Warrenton; near Bellona Arsenal in Chesterfield County; along the North Western Turnpike near Cheat River; and notes on fossil collections (1854). 1 vol., 134 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, 1877, Field notes. Geology observed during train journey from Richmond to Philadelphia. April 18-22. 1 vol., 20 pp.
  - William B. Rogers, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - William B. Rogers, n.d., Report. "Copy of the Report made by Prof. Wm. B. Rogers relative to Walton's Gold Mine in Louisa Co., Virginia." Copied by Forrest Shepherd. 2 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, n.d., Field notes. "Notes respecting Hot Springs and vicinity." 8 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, n.d., Field notes. "Thickness of No. XI on the Potomac below Westernport." 1 p.
    - William B. Rogers, n.d., Field notes. Geology of Augusta Springs vicinity, Little Mountain on the Staunton and Parkersburg Road, and Backbone Mountain. 24 p.
    - William B. Rogers, n.d., Field notes. Vicinity of Sweet Springs, Monroe County. 8 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, n.d., Field notes. "James and Appomattox Rivers in the vicinity of Richmond and Petersburg." 28 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, n.d., Field notes. Geology of the western Virginia Appalachian region. 3 pp.
  - William B. Rogers, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - William B. Rogers, n.d., Field notes. "From Richmond to Charlottesville by stage." Inverted and at back of book, notes on geology of Alleghany and Greenbrier counties. 1 vol., 58 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, n.d., List. "Register of Analysis" of minerals, and analyses not connected with the survey. 1 vol., 212 pp.
    - William B. Rogers, n.d., List. "Levant Series" of rocks, including sections of western Virginia. 1 vol., 85 pp.
  - William B. Rogers, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - William B. Rogers, n.d., List. Promedidicil, Levant, Matinal rocks. 1 vol., unnumbered.
  - William B. Rogers, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - William B. Rogers, n.d., List. "Matinal Rocks," including sections of the Valley of Virginia. 1 vol., pages unnumbered, 3/4 blank.
  - Israel Slade, 1838 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Israel Slade, 1838, Field notes. "Notes on the Burkett's Hole Mountain," in Hardy and Pendleton counties. 19 pp.
  - Israel Slade, 1840 (Box 5, Folder 6)